<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: development | random geekery]]></title>
  <link href="http://finack.com/blog/categories/development/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://finack.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-18T13:31:32-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://finack.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Peter Baker]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What's in a pair]]></title>
    <link href="http://finack.com/blog/2014/01/18/whats-in-a-pair/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-18T12:18:40-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://finack.com/blog/2014/01/18/whats-in-a-pair</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After pairing in some capacity since 2008, I still wonder what makes a good pair. Or even, should I pair? After a great conversation with CK on the way back from Hollywierd, I was reminded about the alternatives to pairing. How pairing offers a different way to do code reviews, discuss a problem, or collaborate on a solution. But as we chatted about the merits of pairing, I was more struck with how I can not imagine working any other way.</p>

<p>What is it about pairing that makes me want to create a personal manifesto that demands &mdash; no is an ultimatum &mdash; that I shall only work in environments where pairing is the norm. Where pairing&rsquo;s value is not in question, and my fellow engineers are looking to enhance, not destroy the value of pairing.</p>

<p>There are mechanical aspects of pairing that can be compared to soloing: code reviews, discussing feature requirements, making architectural decisions. But then there is the larger social or interpersonal dynamics of pairing: constant communication and interativity. I was first made aware of this value when talking to Rob Mee @ Pivotal one day about pairing and why pairing is one of the cornerstone to some software development methodologies.</p>

<p>When you properly pair, you are constantly communicating about all of the mechanical things one does as an engineer. You are also communicating about all those other hard to institutionalize practices that makes a great software development team: style, working agreements, to refactor or not, should I chase that rabbit down this hole.</p>

<p>There are potential downsides to pairing though. You can exclude people who&rsquo;s preference is on a less interactive style (e.g. introverts). Interpersonal issues can be amplified. It can be done wrong and the mechanical and community values can be lost. I worry about excluding people but I also worry about the alternative of either making pairing optional or diluted to where the value of constant communication is lost.</p>

<p>I have found the alternatives to pairing to be a difficult as well. Code reviews are very distracting and a typically a major context shift. The community values of style, joint decision making, etc, require more formal processes to maintain and implement. I have seen organizations where pairing is not the norm and their mechnical and community engineering practices are amazing. So it is not to say that pairing is the only way.</p>

<p>But, pairing is probably the only way for me at this time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
