<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: general | random geekery]]></title>
  <link href="http://finack.com/blog/categories/general/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://finack.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-01T12:34:54-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://finack.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Peter Baker]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[REBOOT]]></title>
    <link href="http://finack.com/blog/2013/12/31/reboot/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-31T12:34:11-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://finack.com/blog/2013/12/31/reboot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After more then a year of inactivity I have decided to reboot this place. And by rebooting I mean <code>posts.all.map &amp;:destroy</code>.</p>

<p>I could have saved a couple of the older posts, but inspiration and mainly the avoidance of perspiration has influenced me to just save the bits and throw the old out.</p>

<p>It is New Years and it is a bit cliché to restart a blog but it also happens to align with a good chunk of time off. I have found the 2-weeks staycation to be very rejuvenating. I have spent the time working on the brewery (more to come), doing odd chores around the house, and getting to better know JavaScript, CoffeeScript, and Ember.</p>

<p>A couple years ago I had a similar experience where I spent a week with friends in Hawaii diving and refactoring <a href="http://github.com/finack/dotfiles">my terminal setup</a>. That investment of time has gone a long way as I use it daily. To continue on that path I am going to borrow an idea from <a href="https://twitter.com/r00k">Ben Orenstein</a> about tool sharping. Check out the <a href="http://rubyrogues.com/129-rr-sharpening-tools-with-ben-orenstein/">Ruby Rogue&rsquo;s podcast</a> for more details (and check back here for future blog posts).</p>

<p><blockquote><p></p></p><p><p>we&rsquo;re sorry<br/><br/>but you&rsquo;re no longer needed<br/><br/>or wanted<br/><br/>or even cared about here <br/><br/>machines can do a better job than you<br/><br/>this is what you get for asking questions<br/></p><footer><strong>Dead Kennedys</strong> <cite>Soup Is Good Food</cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>So with out further ado, I christen my rebooted blog with a <a href="https://untappd.com/b/cleophus-quealy-beer-company-figgy-piggy/235867">lovely beer</a> and some salami.</p>

<h2>Credits</h2>

<p>Much gratititude to so many people who make even a meek little blog possible. It is always amazing to reflect on how much is built on the layers of OSS</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a></li>
<li><a href="http://https://github.com/mikeclarke/villainy-octopress-theme">Villainy Octopresss Theme</a></li>
<li>DCM&rsquo;s use of Music Quotes in his blog, random but generally amusing</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
